<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>secret room assistant</name>
    <directory>secret room assistant</directory>
    <id>3755814659</id>
    <description>[b]A smart minimap assistant for finding Secret Rooms without simply revealing them.[/b]

Secret Room Assistant highlights likely Secret Room candidates, remembers failed bomb checks, and rules out impossible entrances, so you can spend fewer bombs on guesswork and more time actually playing the run.

[h1]Secret Room Assistant[/h1]

Tired of wasting bombs on walls that were never going to open?

Secret Room Assistant adds visual hints to your minimap, helping you identify likely Secret Room locations using only information that is already available to the player. It does not reveal hidden floor data or simply give you the answer - it acts more like a smart notebook that tracks room layout, valid candidates, blocked entrances, and failed bomb checks for you.

[h2]What it does[/h2]

The mod analyzes the visible map layout and marks possible Secret Room positions directly on the minimap:

[list]
[*][b]![/b] - strong candidate, usually connected to at least three known rooms
[*][b]?[/b] - possible candidate, usually connected to two known rooms
[*][b]X[/b] - ruled out location, blocked by obstacles or already tested with a bomb
[/list]

Markers work on both the small minimap and the expanded map.

[h2]Compatibility notes[/h2]

[list]
[*]Designed for [b]The Binding of Isaac: Repentance+[/b]
[*]Requires [b]MinimapAPI[/b]
[*]Standard Secret Rooms are currently supported
[*]Candidate hints are disabled in Greed and Greedier modes
[/list]

[h2]Requirement[/h2]

MinimapAPI:
https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=1978904635

[h2]Feedback[/h2]

This mod is still being improved. If you find a room layout where the assistant marks something incorrectly, please leave a comment with a screenshot or a short description of the floor situation.</description>
    <version>1.4</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Rooms"/>
    <tag id="Floors"/>
</metadata>
